# Misja Pronk

Pijlpunt 16, 2496SN Den Haag // LinkedIn // website // misja@prorexconsultancy.nl // 0643459495

## **Profile**

Misja is analytically strong, creative and has an eye for quality and results. He has good communication skills and is an excellent trainer and coach. He works well under pressure and adapts quickly to requirements. He enjoys complex functional and technical challenges and is self-motivated but can also motivate others. Misja has more than 5 years of experience in designing and developing data solutions and specializes in metadata-driven solutions. Misja keeps up to date with the latest technologies and enjoys using them to help clients take the next steps with their data.

# Experience

ProRex Consultancy // Data & Analytics Consultant March 2022 – Present As a freelance consultant I can help clients with the following: Designing and building data solutions in Microsoft Azure, Improving existing solutions, Implementing CI/CD pipelines and giving training in various Azure technologies.

GoDataDriven // Data & Analytics Consultant

September 2020 – Feb 2022

Designed and built data solutions for the following clients: NationaleNederlanden, Stedin, Witteveen+Bos, Intergamma, VeiligheidNL. During my time at
GoDataDriven I have also: built the infrastructure for a reusable data platform (which is sold to customers), supported sales in improving their offerings and given presentations

## Macaw // Data & Analytics Consultant

to share knowledge about new technologies.

September 2019 - August 2020

Designed and built data solutions for the following

clients: *SamenGezond, Sustainovate, Henkel*. During my tenure at macaw, I was part of the technology comittee additionally responsible for the following: Revising the Macaw data platform, recording best practices and mentoring juniors.

## Motion 10 // Data & Analytics Consultant

January 2018 - August 2019

Designed and built data solutions for the following clients: *De Goudse verzekeringen, Het Nieuwe Instituut, Van Gogh Museum, Samskip, ABN AMRO, Croonwolter&dros, TBI, Marlink.* During my time at Motion10, I also created training materials, trained clients and consultants, and developed a reusable data platform.

## Vixion // Full Stack Developer

April 2015 - October 2016

Worked on a single sign-on (SSO) solution for small and medium -sized enterprises (SME).

## Education

## The Hague University of Applied Sciences

2012 - 2017

**Major subjects**: data architecture, software architecture, analysis and software design, application building and management, process management and requirements engineering.

*Minor subjects*: software security, business information management, intercultural communications, business cases and graph databases.

## **Diplomas & Certificates**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology – Graduated 2017 MCSA: Data Engineering with Azure - Certified 2018

MCSE: Data Management and Analytics - Certified 2018

# Skills

### Azure Technologies

Azure, Databricks, Azure Synapse, Log Analytics, Data Factory, Azure Data Lake Storage, Virtual Machines, Azure Functions, App Service, Container Instances, Container Registry, Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Database for PostgreSQL, Azure DevOps, Logic Apps, Azure Policy, Azure Cost Management and Billing, Azure Advisor, Key Vault, Azure Active Directory, Azure Blob Storage, Azure Files, Virtual Network, Private Link

## Databases & Data Management

Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Delta Lake, Databricks, Spark, DBT, FiveTran, Great Expectations, Azure SQL Database, Neo4j, Elastic search

## Programming

Java, C#, SQL, Cypher, PowerShell, Python, USQL, Git, DevOps, GitHub, Gitlab

#### Containers & Cloud

Docker, Azure, Cloud Custodian, Terraform, ARM

## Languages & Soft Skills

Presenting, training English, Dutch, Spanish

## **Project Management**

Agile, Waterfall, Scrum

## Techniques

Dimensional Modeling, Data Modeling, Graph modelling, UML

# **Projects**

#### Vattenfall // Data Engineer & Solution Architect // 6 months

Vattenfall is a Swedish energy and utility company. They have a data warehouse based on Azure using the following services Analysis services, Synapse and Databricks, which was troubled with performance, maintenance, cost problems. I was part of a new scrum team responsible for migrating this data warehouse to a modern Lakehouse architecture based on Databricks and DBT (a database build tool). As a Data Engineer and Solution Architect, I was responsible for: Designing the new architecture, determining the technology stack, set up the infrastructure, setup CI/CD pipelines, training the team into the chosen technologies, extracting the data source using Databricks notebooks (PySpark) and quality assurance.

#### VeiligheidNL // Data Engineer // 1 month

VeiligheidNL process data related to traffic incidents for the Dutch government. This data is supplied by hospitals and other medical instances. Due to GDPR regulations they need to filter any data that is not related to traffic incidents. A machine learning model was build in order achieve this. This model was incorporated in a public API where hospitals can upload their information. As a Data Engineer, I was responsible for: Designing the API, Building the API and improving CI/CD.

#### Clay // Data Engineer // 2 months

Clay had a couple of bad performing Databricks jobs that needed improvement. They also wanted to include elastic search into their data platform. Due to allot of changes within the development team there was no consensus on how to build and maintain the solution. As a Data Engineer, I was responsible for: Building a component for Elastic Search, Improving the development practices, Improving CI/CD and reworking the bad performing Databricks jobs.

#### Nationale Nederlanden // Data Engineer // 11 months

During the implementation of Nationale Nederlanden's reusable data platform for a business unit, it became clear that the data platform did not meet the requirements. The GDD team designed and built a new data platform with terraform, databricks, synapse, purview, great expectations, data lake gen 2. We also implemented automated infrastructure testing and improved the CI/CD pipelines. The project ended with a successful implementation of the data platform. As a Data Engineer, I was responsible for: designing the infrastructure structure, rebuilding ETL, improving CI/CD, knowledge sharing, and implementing the data quality component.

#### Stedin // Data & Analytics Consultant // 1 month

Stedin had just migrated his on-premises data warehouse (Oracle, Informatica) to a Big Data platform in Azure with HDInsights, Informatica, and SQL Server Managed Instance. After the migration, Stedin was struggling to keep the platform running. They asked for an assessment of the current solution. I was responsible for interviewing stakeholders, identifying the technical and organizational issues, and creating an improvement plan.

#### Witteveen+bos // Data Analytics Consultant // 3 months

Witteveen+bos is a consulting and engineering company consisting of many independent business units. To monitor the performance of the business units, the idea of KPI dashboards was developed. A proof-of-concept showed that there was a need to develop a data platform that would allow the creation of KPI dashboards. My role was to design a suitable solution which consisted of a modern data platform using Microsoft Azure. I was responsible for creating the project plan, initial architecture and designs based on the architecture.

#### Henkel // Data Engineer // 6 months

Henkel is a German manufacturer of beauty and care products, among others. There was a need for a central data platform that would incorporate API sources such as Google, Searchmetrics and Facebook. Henkel wanted to launch a pilot project to investigate the feasibility of a new data platform that would incorporate these APIs. I was responsible for defining the pilot, implementing Searchmetrics ELT and leading the development team of 7 developers.

#### Intergamma // Data and Analytics Consultant // 2 months

Intergamma had a legacy data warehouse and analytics platform based on IBM Netezza. As part of their strategy to become a data-driven company, they needed a modern data platform. I was responsible for formulating the requirements, outlining the different cloud scenarios (AWS, Azure, GCP) and developing a roadmap.

#### Sustainovate // Solution Architect // 2 months

Sustainovate is a data processing company for shipping companies. It creates data solutions (reports and metrics) that are shared between shipping companies, environmental organizations, and universities. Their current data platform was not designed to meet the new privacy, accountability and security requirements. I was responsible for identifying the requirements, creating the use cases, and designing the technical solution.

#### Samengezond (Menzis) // Data Engineer // 10 months

Samengezond is an initiative by Menzis to encourage people to adopt healthy behaviors. They developed an app that stores data in Dacadoo. The data platform needed to integrate the app's data with other data sources like Mailchimp and Typeform in real time. I was responsible for designing the Azure architecture, developing the integration with the APIs and other resources, and delivery.

#### Het Nieuwe Instituut // Data Engineer // 4 months

Het Nieuwe Instituut has an obligation to the government to report on the progress and budgets of long-term projects. For this they wanted to use a data platform and accompanying reports. I developed the ETL of the local systems (AFAS and Exact), implemented and set up the Azure environment and was responsible for the realization of the entire project.

#### De Goudse Verzekeringen // Solution Architect // 3 months

De Goudse verzekeringen was designing a new enterprise-wide IT architecture. This included setting up an integrated data architecture with the requirement to use MarkLogic due to previous investments. The old on-premises data warehouse also needed to be migrated to Azure. My role as solution architect was to support the enterprise architects, create the target architecture for the solution and plan the migration.

#### Van Gogh Museum // Solution Architect // 3 months

VGM wanted to gain insight into the customer behavior of its visitors. This information was stored in various systems. For this, a central data platform had to be developed. I developed the ETL for local systems and APIs, provided and set up Azure environments, trained the staff and was responsible for the implementation of the project.

#### Samskip // Data Engineer // 3 months

Samskip is a transportation company that has grown through numerous acquisitions. Due to the complex and fragmented IT landscape, there was an urgent need to make data centrally available. A

data platform was developed and a pilot report was created to demonstrate the value of the platform. I developed ETL from AS400 (DB2) and other on-premises systems, implemented and configured Azure environments, translated logic from QlikView reports into data marts, and trained staff on the use of Data Factory.

#### ABN AMRO Pensioenfonds // Solution Architect // 4 months

ABN AMRO had several applications and systems in the UK that needed to be relocated before Brexit. The following actions needed to be taken: Retire the SAS solution (pension consolidation), migrate the on-premises client server Microsoft Access applications to Azure and migrate the customer portal ABN AMRO to Azure. My task was to design the new cloud architecture in view of the migration, to make agreements with suppliers in connection with the replacement of SAS, to monitor all implementations and to be responsible for the quality of the solution.

#### Croonwolter&dros // Solution Architect // 3 months

Design of a solution architecture for Croonwolter&dross' new data warehouse. The current situation was an on-premises solution characterized by performance issues and unable to support future advanced analytics applications. Principles for the new data platform: integration of new data sources (including an Acto ERP system and the Acto data warehouse), migration to Azure Cloud, support for streaming data and advanced analytics, halving of ETL process times, manageability by own staff.

#### TBI // Data Engineer // 4 months

Design and implementation of a data platform for the Shared Service Center (SSC), which is part of TBI. The SSC provides IT services to 17 companies in the construction and infrastructure sectors. Given the large number of data sources (hundreds) that needed to be integrated into the data platform, I developed and designed a metadata-driven solution to solve this problem. I set up CI/CD, defined the development standard, trained the client's staff, and migrated the SSIS functionality to Azure Data Factory.

#### Marlink // Data Engineer // 7 months

Marlink is a company that provides mobile services to the maritime sector. The company accumulates huge amounts of data that needs to be analyzed to improve its services. The company needed a Big Data platform to process these volumes of data. One of Marlink's requirements was that the platform should be developed based on PAAS services, preferably with a pay-as-you-go model. My role was to design the platform, set up CI/CD, define development standards for a multidisciplinary team of 5 people, develop ELT for the Boskalis pilot and be responsible for Q&A.

#### Vixion // Sofware Engineer // 8 months

worked with a team of 7 software engineers on an SSO (Single Sign-On as a Service) solution. I was primarily responsible for building the API, creating the database, developing the application and acting as a translator between the domain expert and the development team.